Approach Archives
Approach Archives
- Magazines
  - Miscellaneous magazines
    - ERA, Fall 1964; organ of the Philomathean Society of the University of Pennsylvania editor-in-chief: Daniel Alkon; with letter to Elliot Herman from advertising manager (Box 10)
    - EVERGREEN REVIEW, March-April 1960; no 12; editor: Barney Rossett, published by the Grove Press, N.Y. City (Box 10)
    - EVIDENCE, Winter 1962; no 4; Canadian; editors: Alan Bevan, Kenneth Wells, Toronto (Box 10)
    - FELLOWSHIP: magazine of the Fellowship of Reconciliation, 1 Jan 1932; May 1967; Vol 23 no 1, containing Thomas Merton's essay "The Root of War", Vol. 33 no 5; editor Alfred Hassler, Nyack, N.Y. (Box 10)
    - FINE ARTS MAGAZINE, 1961; no. 6; published annually during the University of Connecticut Fine Arts Festival; Lewis Turco editor, Sharon Herlihy and James Leheny co-editors, Storrs, Conn. (Box 10)
    - FOCUS: to focus our minds inward towards integration, June 1951; mimeographed; Peter Docili editor: designer, The Sweeping Leaves Press, Pendle Hill, Wallingford, Pa. (Box 10)
    - FORUM, Winter 1961-62; Vol 2 no 2; editors: Merrill and Frances M. Rippy, with letter from Frances Rippy; Ball State Teachers College, Muncie, Ind. (Box 10)
    - FORUM ECHOES III, Spring 1966; collection of poems by members of the Dayton, Ohio Poetry Forum (Box 10)
    - FOXFIRE, Spring 1967; Vol 1 no 1, 2d printing; published by English Dept at the Rabun Gap-Nacogdoches School, Rabun Gap, Ga.; editors Lynne Allen and Tommy Wilson, with letter from the editors (Box 10)
    - FREELANCE: the magazine for freelance writers, July 1965; Vol 1 no 1; executive editor: Jerry Gustav Hasford IV; Russellville, Ala. (Box 10)
    - FURIOSO: a magazine of poetry, Summer 1941; Vol 1 no 4; editors: James J. Angleton and E. Reed Whittemore, Jr., New Haven Conn. (Box 10)
    - GADFLY (THE), Feb. 1961; published by the students at Wilson College, Chambersburg, Pa., chief editor: Sara Makemes (Box 10)
    - GALLERY SERIES ONE, 1967; Poets, Harper Square Press, Chicago, Ill. (Box 10)
    - GENERAL MAGAZINE AND HISTORICAL CHRONICLE (THE), Fall 1957; Vol 60 no 1, with poems by Sam Bradley; published by the General Alumni Society of the University of Pennsylvania, Neda Westlake, editor (Box 10)
    - GEORGIA REVIEW (THE), Spring, 1956; Vol 10 no 1; published by the University of Georgia, Athens, Ga., editor John Olin Eidson (Box 10)
    - GOOSEBERRY I, Spring 1964; Vol 1 no 1; Mt. Pleasant, Pa., editors John and Susan Cornillon, with letter from editors (Box 10)
    - HANDLE (THE), Fall 1963; inscribed to Albert Fowler by Will Inman who had poems in this issue; published at the University of Pennsylvania, address Houston Hall, Marc Rosenberg, editor (Box 10)
    - HANGING LOOSE, Fall 1966; Winter/Spring 1967,; Summer 1967; editor Dick Lourie, published in N.Y. City (Box 10)
    - HASSLE, May 1963; no 1, with letter from Owens; edited by H. W. Stopher III, Braxton Bryant, Tary K. Owens, Christopher Teele, John Moyer, at Austin, Texas (Box 10)
    - HAVERFORD REVUE (THE), Spring 1960; Vol 1; published by Haverford College students; editor: Jonathan Z. Smith (Box 10)
    - HERBARIST (THE), 1966; #32, inscribed to the Fowlers by Mina C. Saunders; publication of the Herb Society of America, Boston, Mass. (Box 10)
    - HORNSPOON, 1961; 1962; Vol 11, Vol 12; published by the Associated Students of Long Beach State College, Long Beach, Calif. (Box 10)
    - INSCAPES, 1962; published by students at Rosemont College, Rosemont, Pa (Box 10)
    - INSIDE BORDENTOWN, a newspaper published of, by and for the inmates of this reformatory, editor-in-chief: William Goode, Bordentown, N.J. (Box 10)
    - LITERARY ARTPRESS, Spring 1960; Fall 1960,; Spring 1961; Vol 1 no 2, Vol 2 no 1, Vol 2 no 2; published under the auspices of the English Dept. and Ass. Student Body at Eastern Washington College of Education, Cheney Wash. (Box 10)
    - LITERARY SKETCHES, a magazine of interviews, reviews & memorabilia, Apr 1966; Dec 1966; Vol 6 no 4, Vol 6 no 12; Mary Lewis B. Chapman editor, Williamsburg, Va. (Box 10)
    - LITERARY TIMES, Dec. 1963; Mar 1966,; Mar 1963; Vol 3 no 2, Vol 4 no 5, Vol 2 no 4; Chicago, Ill. editor: Jay Robert Nash (Box 10)
    - LITUANUS, 1958; undated; Vol 4 no 4, Vol 7 no 4; Lithuanian Collegiate Quarterly, Brooklyn, N.Y. (Box 10)
    - LONDON MAGAZINE (THE), May 1956; Vol 3 no 5; British; editor: John Lehman (Box 10)
    - LONG WAY HOME (THE), Dec. 1966; composed and compiled by the writing fiction class, Southeast Community College, University of Kentucky, Cumberland, Ky. (Box 10)
    - MANHATTAN REVIEW: a little magazine of emerging poetry & fiction, 1966; Numbah [sic] One, Volyoom one numbah two [sic]; editors: Edythe Dimond, Marjorie Marshall, Eric Oatman, NY City (Box 10)
    - MIDWEST QUARTERLY (THE): a journal of contemporary thought, July 1965; Vol 6 no 4, with Sam Bradley's poems; published at Kansas State College of Pittsburg, Dudley T. Cornish editor-in-chief (Box 10)
    - MILAN MI-LINE, Spring 1962; Summer 1962; Vol 1 no 2, Vol 1 no 3; published to give training in purposeful & useful writing by the men of the Milan Federal Correctional Institution at Milan, Mich. (Box 10)
    - MPT (Modern Poetry in Translation), Summer 1966; Spring 1967; no 2, no 3; British; editors Ted Hughes and Daniel Weissbrot, London, England (Box 10)
    - MUSIC WORLD, Dec. 1966; May 1968; Vol 2 no 12, Vol 4 no 5 (Box 10)
    - Narceja: revista trimestral de poesia, 1959; no 3, inscribed to the Fowlers by John Nist; editors: Percy Garnier, Domingos Paolielo, Antonio Ramos Rosa, Edgar Bayley, John Nist, Sao Paulo, Brazil (Box 10)
    - NEW CAMPUS REVIEW, May 1966; Vol 1 no 1; published at Metropolitan State College, Denver, Colo. (Box 10)
    - NEW FRONTIERS, May 1962; Winter 1964-65; Vol 7 no 3, Vol 10 no 1; published by the students of Fairfield University, Fairfield, Conn. (Box 10)
    - NEW MEXICO QUARTERLY, Winter 1954-55; Spring 1955; Vol 24 no 4, Vol 25 no 1; published by the University of New Mexico, Albuquerque, N.M., editor: Kenneth Lash (Box 10)
    - NEW STATESMAN, 2/25/66; British; London (Box 10)
    - NEWSPAPER COLLECTOR (THE), Vol 3 no 1, Vol 3 no 2, Vol 4 no 1 issue #11;, Vol 4 no 2 issue #12; newspaper, magazine, book collecting San Francisco, Calif. (Box 10)
    - NEW WEST (THE), Nov. 1966; no 1; Ocean Park, Calif. editor: Arnold L. Kaye (Box 10)
    - NUCLEUS (New Zealand), Aug. 1961; Number 4 (Box 10)
    - NUMBERS (New Zealand), March 1957; July 1958,; Feb. 1959,; Oct. 1959; #6, #8, #9, #10 (Box 10)
    - ODYSSEY: explorations in contemporary poetry and the arts, 1959; Vol 1, no 4; editors: R.R. Cuscaden, Ronald Offen, Chicago, Ill. (Box 10)
    - OUTPOSTS, Winter 1958; Number 39; British; edited by Howard Sergeant, London (Box 10)
    - PANACHE, presenting new writers using the "hiccough" effect introducing contents before introducing itself, 1965; Vol 1 no 1; editors: the contributors, N.Y. City (Box 11)
    - PATHWAYS: literary magazine, May 1966; Vol 1 no 2; mimeographed; sponsored by and for Pen & Pencil Set, Edgar L. Glines editor, Vacaville, Calif. (Box 11)
    - PAX ET LIBERTAS, Jan-Mar 1965; Oct-Dec 1967,; Jan-Mar. 1968; Vol 30 no 1, Vol 32 no 4, Vol 33 no 1; published by the Women's International League for Peace and Freedom, Reading, England, editor Phoebe Cusden (Box 11)
    - PEACE: the Drop City Newsletter, Mar. '67; Vol 2 no 3; Trinidad, Calif. (Box 11)
    - PEGASUS, 1956; #16 (Vol 4 no 4); editors: Kate Beltrone, Robert Clairmont, Lucile Coleman, Mary E. Keller, Naomi Marcato, Anca Vrbovska, N.Y. City (Box 11)
    - PENDULUM (THE) of time and the arts, reflecting the culture and charm of the past, Nov-Dec 1963; Jan-Feb 1964; Vol 7 no 50, Vol 7 no 51; mimeographed; Arthur W. Muller editor and publisher Glendale, N.Y. (Box 11)
    - PERSONALIST (THE) an international review of philosophy, religion and literature, Jul 1960; Vol 41 no 3; W.H. Werkmeister editor (Box 11)
    - PERSPECTIVE: a quarterly of literature and the arts, Summer 1949; Summer 1954; Vol 2 no 4, Vol 7 no 2; editors: at University of Louisville, Louisville, Ky. Mona Van Duyn, Jarvis Thurston, Sherman Conrad; from Washington University, St. Louis, Mo. same editors with Ralph Nash (Box 11)
    - PINNACLE of literature, Autumn 1960; Summer 1961; editor Elise Pinkerton Steart, Toledo, Ohio (Box 11)
    - PODIUM (Dutch) litterair maandblad, May/June 1952; Vol 8 no 3 (Box 11)
    - POESIA DE ESPANA, 1963; #9; Spanish; Madrid, Spain (Box 11)
    - POET'S MISSION (THE), Fall 1962; Spring 1963,; Fall 1963; Vol 2 part 2 no 3, Vol 3 part 1 no 4, Vol 3 part 2 no 5; mimeographed; editor: D. Shepard, N.Y. City (Box 11)
    - POET & CRITIC: a folder of poetry and criticism, Fall 1964; Vol 1 no 1; William Tillson, editor, Purdue University, Lafayette, Ind., File #1, 1961; revived at Iowa State University at Iowa, Richard Gustafson editor: new focus - a magazine of verse, a workshop in print, a forum of opinion (Box 11)
    - POETRY DIAL, Springtime 1961; Vol 1 no 2; editor: J. William Myers, South Bend, Ind. (Box 11)
    - POETRY DIGEST: America's best-loved poetry magazine, Feb-Mar 1957; Vol 4 no 2; published by National Press, John De Stefano editor, Milldale, Conn. (Box 11)
    - POETRY NEWSLETTER, Apr-Mar 1965; no 3; editor: Wallace Depew, N.Y. City, mimeographed (Box 11)
    - POTWICK PAPERS, Jan. 1962; Vol 1 no 1 with letter from Butcher; mimeographed; British; editor: Peter R. Butcher, East Finchley, London (Box 11)
    - POLITICS, Sep 1945; Nov. 1945; Vol 2 no 9, Vol 2 no 11; editor: Dwight Macdonald, N.Y. City (Box 11)
    - QUASIMODO QUARTERLY REVIEW: the magazine of the outside generation, Spring 1962; mimeographed; editor Bill Robins, C.H. Taylor III, E.T. Guidotti, Mexico City College, Mexico City (Box 11)
    - QUICKSILVER: a quarterly magazine of poetry, Spring 1962; Vol 15 no 1, with promotion; editors: Grace Ross and Mabel M. Kuykendall, Taos, N.M. (Box 11)
    - RAMPARTS: The National Catholic Journal, March 1963; Vol 1 no 5; editor-in-chief: Edward M. Keatin, Menlo Park, Calif. (Box 11)
    - REACTIONS: revue litteraire internationale, 1966; directeur: Jean Beuelin, Bienne Suisse (Box 11)
    - RELIGIOUS THEATRE, Fall 1964; Number 1; editors: James R. Carlson, Warren Kliewer, St. Petersburg, Fla. (Box 11)
    - REYNARD: the magazine of the Quaker fellowship of the arts, 1959-1962; British; editor: Katharine M. Wilson, London (Box 11)
      Vol 4 no 2, Jan. 1959; no 3, May 1959
      conference number 1959
      1961 issue
      1962 issue
    - SAN FRANCISCO EVENING LAMP: a magazine of life, literature, art, Americana, Fall 1963; #21 (Box 11)
    - SCOPE: a literary review, June 1963; #9; published by and for the students of English 55 and 110 at the University of San Francisco, David M. Kirk editor (Box 11)
    - SEASON: a Quarterly on contemporary human problems, Winter 1963; Vol 1 no 4; published by the Dominican Fathers of the Province of the Holy Name, Oakland, Calif.; editor: Janko Zagar, O.P. (Box 11)
    - SESSION, Spring 1963; Vol 1 no 1; published at Wabash College, Crawfordsville, Ind.; editors: Ben Banicki, Allan Dooley, Gary Mohler (Box 11)
    - SEVEN (formerly The Lantern), 1963; Vol 1 no 3; editor: James Neill Northe, Oklahoma City, Okla. (Box 11)
    - SHENANDOAH: The Washington and Lee University Review, Winter 1959; Spring 1962; Vol 1 no 2, Vol 13 no 3; editor Paxton Davis; editor for '62 issue: Cecil D. Epy Jr. (Box 11)
    - SHORT STORY INTERNATIONAL, Nov. 1963; editor J. Malcolm Morris (Box 11)
    - SMITH ALUMNAE QUARTERLY, April 1967; Vol 58 no 3, containing reprint of Constance Carrier's poem on p. 27 (Box 11)
    - SMOKY HILL REVIEW, Winter 1966; Vol 1 no 1, with letter from the editor; produced by the publications committee of the Division of Language, Literature & speech, Fort Hays Kansas State College; editor: Robert Day (Box 11)
    - SORTIE, Fall 1965; Fall 1966; #1, #2; produced by the Donna Crouse Workshop Freeport Long Island, to introduce writers to editors and others (Box 11)
    - SOUTH AND WEST: an international literary quarterly, Winter 1963; Vol 2 no 3, with newsletter and application for membership in the S & W brochure club for poetry; Fort Smith Ark.; editor: Sue Abbott Boyd (Box 11)
    - SOUTHWEST REVIEW, Summer 1960; Vol 45 no 3, (annual literary number); published by Southern Methodist University, Dallas, Texas; editor Allen Maxwell, asst. editor Margaret L. Hartley (Box 11)
    - SOUTH ATLANTIC QUARTERLY (THE), Autumn 1958; Vol 57 no 4; published by Duke University; editorial board: R. Taylor Cole, B.U. Rachford, Herman Salinger, Lionel Stevenson, Arlin Turner, managing editor: William B. Hamilton (Box 11)
    - SOUTHERLY: a literary magazine, the organ of the English Assn, Sydney Branch, Australia, editor R.G. Howarth, Number 2, Bernard O'Dowd number, 1953 (Box 11)
    - SPECTRUM, Spring-Summer 1959; Vol 3 no 2; published by Associated Students of the University of Calif. Santa Barbara; editor Kerry Gough (Box 11)
    - SPIRIT: a magazine of poetry, May 1959; Vol 23 no 2; published by the Catholic Poetry Society of America; editor: John Gillan Brunini (Box 11)
    - STEM: a magazine of poetry, prose, philosophy and religion published bi-monthly for rational righters and reasonable readers who read and rite, Feb-Mar 1962; editor: James Granville Tampa, Fla. (Box 11)
    - STEP LADDER (THE), Winter 1959; Spring 1959; Vol 42 no 3, with letter to Sam Bradley from Moon, and Vol 42 no 4; originally published by Order of Bookfellows, George Steele Seymour and Flora Warren Seymour founders; now represented by Knox College, Galesburg, Ill.; editor: Samuel Moon (Box 11)
    - THIS AND...exists for the sake of existence; is what its name implies, of the moment and of whatever may follow, 1967; no 10; editor: Michael Garner, mimeographed, N.Y. City (Box 11)
    - TRIAD: poetry, art, music, 1958; 1959; published by William and Anne Byler, New Haven Conn.; with press release (Box 11)
    - UNICORN PRESS, 1967; undated; Santa Barbara, Calif.; editor Alan Brilliant (Box 11)
      Winter/Spring 1967 catalogue
      contents page from Unicorn Journal: an anthology of the finest in belles-lettres
      contributors' notes (from Unicorn Folio #1)
      Poems by Nikolai Norshen and Miriam Waddingham (from Series 2)
      Two Poems by George Hitchcock (from Series 2)
      Teo Savory broadside
      Seferis Postal Poem
      Snyder Postal Poem
    - WABASH REVIEW (THE), Winter 1961; Vol 9 no 1; published at Wabash College, Wabash, Ind.; editors: G.T. Mohler, Eugene Nelson, J.P. Seaton (Box 11)
    - WASHINGTON INTERNATIONAL ARTS LETTER:, Sep 1966; Vol 5 no 8; letter service and digest concerning 20th century patronage, support programs and developments, founded by Daniel Millsaps III, 42nd letter (Box 11)
    - WE OFFER..., Jan-Mar 1963; Vol 1 no 1 (new series) with blank for poetry competition entry; international quarterly of the Poetry Guild; British; editor: John Hoffman (Box 11)
    - W-HOLLOW HARVEST, June 1967; Vol 1 no 6; magazine for Jesse Stuart buffs; Cincinnati Ohio (Box 11)
    - WISCONSIN STUDIES IN CONTEMPORARY LITERATURE, Spring-Summer 1960; Vol 1 no 2; published at the University of Wisconsin, Madison, Wis.; managing editor: Alan R. Goldberg (Box 11)
    - WRITER'S EXCHANGE (THE), 1962-1963; bi-monthly magazine for the use and enjoyment of writers; motto: simplicity with quality; Frederic, Wis.; editor: Ruth Bunker Christiansen; mimeographed (Box 11)
      Vol 2 no 1 Jan-Feb 1962
      Vol 2 no 4, July-Aug. 1962
      Vol 2 no 5, Sep-Oct 1962
      Vol 2 no 6, Nov-Dec 1962
      Vol 3 no 1, Jan-Feb. 1963
      Vol 3 no 2, Mar-Apr 1963
      Vol 3 no 3, May-Jun 1963
    - WRITER'S NOTES & QUERIES: the friendliest magazine in print, Dec 1962; Vol 12 no 1, with notice from editors; solely owned and edited by Eino Hendrik Johnson and Evelyn Pauline Johnson; Calhoun City, Miss. (Box 11)
    - XENIA: a magazine of poetry and comment, Fall 1965; No. 1; edited by Stuart McCarrell and Robert Burleigh; Chicago, Ill. (Box 11)
  - Library bulletins
    - The Lilly Library, Indiana University, Three Centuries of American Poetry: An Exhibition of original Printings (Box 9)
    - Princeton University, Princeton University Library Chronicle, 1966-1968 (Box 11)
      Vol 27 no 2, Winter 1966
      Vol 29 no 1, Autumn 1967
      Vol 29 no 2, Winter 1968
    - Princeton University, Wilde and the Nineties: An Essay and an Exhibition by Richard Ellmann, E.D.H. Johnson, Alfred L. Bush, Princeton, 1966 (Box 11)
    - Syracuse University, Syracuse Poems 1965, selected with foreword by Delmore Schwartz, Syracuse, #218, 1968 (Box 11)
    - Syracuse University, Syracuse Poems 1966-1967, selected with foreword by George P. Elliott, Syracuse, # 631 (Box 11)
- Miscellaneous items
  - Back issues of APPROACH, 1947-1967 (Box 12)
    issues 4, 6 (2 copies), 7, 27, 31 (2 copies), 32 (3 copies), 34 (3 copies), 35 (3 copies), 36, 37 (3 copies), 38, 39 (3 copies), 40 (3 copies), 41 (3 copies), 42 (3 copies), 43 (2 copies), 44 (3), 45 (3 copies), 46 (3 copies), 49, 51 (3 copies), 52, 54, 63 (3 copies)
  - Bound volumes of APPROACH, 1947-1967; 8 volumes (Box 12)
    no's 1-63
    no 64, containing complete cumulative index for no's 1-64
    cumulative index no's 1-38 (3 copies)
    index to no's 39-42
    index to no's 43-46
    index to no's 47-50
    index to no's 51-54
    index to no's 55-58
  - Berdyaev "On Suicide", 3 copies (Box 12)
  - Expenses and receipts, 3 volumes (Box 13)
  - Names and addresses of subscribers, 4 notebooks (Box 13)
  - Kraus reprints of first 46 issues of APPROACH, 3 volumes (Box 12)